Cezar Chirilă

0040726002823 | contact@cezarchirila.com cezarchirila.com | videos.cezarchirila.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: Romanian

Born: April 5th, 1995 in Suceava (Romania)

Address: str. Tomşa-Vodă, nr 40c, Solca, Suceava, Romania (currently living in Cluj-Napoca)

PROFILE

I am an electronic hobbyist and a current student in Electronics and Telecommunications with a large homemade project base, such as a function generator, audio amplifiers and LED matrix displays.

I have a genuine desire to help people and I am enthusiastic, hardworking and very reliable.

I consider myself to be very tech-savvy, with general knowledge of every specific part of what is considered electrical and electronic engineering, with experience in personal projects.

EDUCATION

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Cluj-Napoca, CJ

Electronics, Telecommunications and the Information Technology

2014-2018

Specialisation: Applied electronics

National College "Petru Rareş", Suceava

Suceava, SV

Profile: Nature science

2010-2014

Languages

Romanian: First language

English: Level C1, Cambridge certificate (CAE)

French: intermediate (speaking, reading); basic (writing)

SKILLS

- Analog and Digital circuit design, especially regarding microcontrollers and power supplies;
- PCB and Schematic Design <u>KiCAD</u>, <u>OrCAD</u>, <u>Eagle</u>;
- Electronic Design Simulation (SPICE simulators);

- Programming languages: <u>C/C++</u> (Advanced)(Microcontrollers: AVR 8-bit, STM32), Java (Advanced), HTML5 / CSS3 / JavaScript (Intermediate), Python(Novice);
- 3D design: Autodesk Fusion 360;
- 3D printing (designing and building the 3D printer plus all software related);
- Media: Photoshop (image processing), Sony Vegas (video editing).

WORK EXPERIENCE AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Hardware Engineer at Continental Summer 2017 Internship at Continental Automotive Systems, Sibiu in Powertrain division Designed a small project as a student and followed along major projects Writer at AllAboutCircuits.com 2016 - present Writing technical articles and documenting various personal projects Volunteer at Unica World Movie Contest August 2016 Editing videos and logistics First prize winner (team effort) Polihack – Embedded Section Spring 2016 Designed and built a fall detection device for the elderly Participant at various Hackathons Spring 2016 Techsylvania Hackaton, HomeHackers at Academy Plus Volunteer at VideoArt video Club 2010-2014

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Projects documented on my blog <u>www.CezarChirila.com</u>:

Built my own 3D printer following the reprap project;

Logistics and video editor for International Contest and multiple contests

- LED matrix coffee table;
- ESP8266 Wi-Fi login sketch;

Technical Articles and Projects designed and documented for www.AllAboutCircuits.com:

- Do-It-Yourself Soldering Station with an ATmega8;
- House-Monitoring Framework with Arduino and Raspberry Pi: The Paranoid App;
- Driving LED arrays with Arduino;
- How to build a class D power amplifier;
- DIY Arduino-Based Sous-Vide Machine.